this is the first ever jetpack race
technically they call them jet Suits now
but jetpack the first ever jet suit race
and we are off and Rowan's on the inside
Freddy's going to try and get her on the
inside it was put on by gravity
Industries the maker of the jet suits
the final round involves five jetpack
Pilots all in the same type of suit
racing around a 1 km long course each
suit has seven engines two in each arm
and three in the back each one shoots
out exhaust at 1,000 mph giving 175 kg
of thrust and propelling people up to 50
mph Pilots use their arms and body
positions to navigate around the course
it's basically how I imagined this when
I was a kid except it can be really
dangerous because of that the race
course is over water and each suit is
equipped with buoyancy devices in case
they fall in which did happen in one of
the preliminary rounds it's also a
relatively short course the racer is
usually completed in less than a minute
because the average flight time for the
suit is about 3 minutes these are
absolutely not meant to be practical
forms of transportation but they are
making every little kid's jetpack dreams
come true including mine so uh he
gravity Industries can I learn how to
fly one if you like fun optimistic
Science and Tech stories follow for more